Guillermo Paz

Front End Developer

Capital Federal, Buenos Aires, Argentina

Summary

I know and love the good parts of JavaScript. I love taking advantage of awesome new browser features, without breaking the experience on IE8. I can write CSS that works on all modern browsers (IE8+, FF, Chrome, Safari).

I keep a close eye on trends and innovations in the field of browser interfaces, JavaScript development and web technologies. I love and desire to experiment with new technologies.

Ability to define and maintain complex and well crafted stylesheets.

5 years developing clean, valid, and compatible websites, libraries and applications.

Professional Experience

2008-Present	Frontend Developer • MercadoLibre I'm a Front End Developer at MercadoLibre. I build Chico UI (MercadoLibre's UI framework). I review the front end code. Also, I research the best practices and teach it to others front end teams to improve their code.I give speeches about web standards, best practices and how do you improve your frontend code.
2007-Present	Independent web developer, front end developer. Speaking, writing, doing training and workshops about open web standards. Occasionally freelancing.
2007–2008	Customer Service • MercadoLibre

Specialties

I have a broad understanding of the full Open Web Stack of technologies:

- Expert level knowledge of the JavaScript language.
- Expert level knowledge of jQuery.
- Expert understanding of web technologies (object-oriented JavaScript, HTML, CSS).
- Expert level knowledge of HTML y CSS.
- Expert at writing semantic and well formed HTML.
- Experience developing JavaScript libraries.
- Experience writing vanilla Javascript.
- Experience with JavaScript libraries (¡Query, Modernizr, Backbone, Underscore).
- Experience with the latest and greatest web standards, including HTML5 and CSS3 (W3C).

- Experience working with REST APIs.
- Experience testing and developing across multiple browsers while maintaining a consistent experience.
- Experience working with graceful degradation y progressive enhancement.
- Experience with Responsive Web Design.
- Experience with NodeJS, Express, Jade, SocketIO and Mongoose.
- Experience with GIT (I absolutely love Github).

Education

2008–2011	Diseñador y Administrador de Sitios Web. Intituto de Arte Multimedial Da Vinci.
2006–2007	First 2 years of Licenciatura en Análisis de Sistemas. Universidad de Buenos Aires (UBA).
2001–2005	Bachiller con Capacitación Laboral en Comunicación Social Insituto Ana María Janer.

Honors and Awards

■ Winner of Facebook Developers World Hack Latin America 2012. The best overall application of Latin America - Buenos Aires, Argentina.

Projects

November 2012	Vierport : It is a component to ease viewport management. You can get the dimensions of the viewport and beyond, which can be quite helpful to perform some checks with JavaScript.
May 2012	Jvent: Event Emitter Class for the browser based on NodeJS EventEmitter.
June 2009	Chico UI : MercadoLibre's a big and complex web site with a lot of needs. Every development and design team needed to be able to build quality and consistent web apps using an agile development process. So we had to find a way to unify the process and guarantee design pattern and user experience quality for every team. And Chico was born.

A lot more of my open source libraries and projects can be found in **my Github account**.

Speaking

In 2012, I gave a speech at **JSconf Argentina** about Chico UI and how it helps MercadoLibre to improve its code using the best practices of frontend and progressive enhancement.

Languages

Spanish: NativeEnglish: Intermediate

Professional interests

- Open web standards
- Front-end architecture
- Web Usability & Accessibility
- Web Development Education
- API design
- Graphic Design